A Guide to the Benjamin Penhollow Shillaber Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #7493-c
Benjamin Penhollow Shillaber Collection
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
7493-c
8 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase 1972 Mar 9
Item Listing
- Letters
  - Benjamin Penhollow Shillaber to Frederick Eugene Partington, 1876 Jun 24; ALS, 1 p.
    [Says he will be happy to receive him in his home; says he is glad that the Partington family did not react indignantly to the follies of their namesake "Mrs. Partington."]
  - Benjamin Penhallow Shillaber to [James Ripley] Osgood, 1877 Apr 7; ALS, 1 p.
    [Requests a copy of [Harriet] Martineau's book; quotes H[osca] Biglow of
    The Biglow Papers
    , by James Russell Lowell; says he is indebted to Osgood.]
  - Benjamin Penhallow Shillaber to Eben[ezer] Lane, Jr., 1878 Dec 6; ALS, 1 p.
    [Provides correct name, as correspondent mistakenly addressed him as P. C. Shillaber.]
  - Benjamin Penhallow Shillaber to R. A. McFadden, Esq., 1882 Mar 4; ALS, 1 p.
    [Assures autograph seeker that it is his true signature.]
  - Benjamin Penhallow Shillaber to "Dear Brother Brewster", Sep 27; ALS, 1 p.
    [Refuses to print an "important document."]
  - Benjamin Penhallow Shillaber to J. T. McCowen, 18 Nov 11; ANS, 1 p.
    [Responds to request for an autograph.]
  - Benjamin Penhallow Shillaber to Mr. Whyatt, Wednesday a.m.; ANS, 1 p.
    [Says he took a bouquet of flowers from Whyatt's store for a school examination in Chelsea and he will square his accounts when they meet.]
- Miscellaneous
  - Quotation by Alexander Pope, signed by Benjamin Penhallow Shillaber, 1873 Oct; Autograph